<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC
  "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
  "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<!--
    Copyright 2015-2017 Hippo

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the  "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS"
    BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Hippo Channel Manager Page Management Support</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Hippo Channel Manager Page Management Support">
      <p>
        This project provides some add-on features like the following:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <code>DocumentCopyingPageCopyEventListener</code> handling <code>PageCopyEvent</code>
          propagated by Hippo Channel Manager,
          in order to copy all the linked documents by the page and its components together,
          when a page is being copied from a channel.
        </li>
        <li>
          <code>DocumentManagementService</code> component to provide document/folder workflow operations.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <subsection name="DocumentCopyingPageCopyEventListener component">
        <p>
          <code>org.onehippo.forge.channelmanager.pagesupport.channel.event.DocumentCopyingPageCopyEventListener</code>
          component copies linked documents in a page and its components from the source channel to the target channel
          on the event of page copying in the channel manager.
        </p>
        <p>
        <code>DocumentCopyingPageCopyEventListener</code> can be extended for some custom needs.<br/>
          In version 1.2.0, the hooks <code>onBeforePageCopyEvent</code> and <code>onAfterPageCopyEvent</code>
          have been introduced. See at the <a href="custom-configuration.html#Extension_Hooks">custom configuration page</a>.
        </p>
       </subsection>
      <subsection name="DocumentManagementService component">
        <p>
          <code>org.onehippo.forge.channelmanager.pagesupport.document.management.DocumentManagementService</code> component is provided to manage document/folder workflows more easily.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section name="Demo Application">
      <subsection name="Demo Application with Hippo CMS 10">
        <p>You can build and run a demo application, which contains all the examples explained in this site documentation.
          The demo application is present in the demo submodule.</p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section name="Testing with Demo Application">
      <p>
        The demo application consists of many different channels.
        This basic testing steps will show how a page in the source (English / US) channel can be copied to
        the target (Dutch / Belgium) channel with the linked document content together as an example.
      </p>
      <p>
        Browse the content folder in the source (English / US) channel.
        You will see three published documents there.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen01.png" alt="Test 1" />
      <p>
        Now, browse the target (Dutch / Belgium) channel. You won't see any documents there yet.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen02.png" alt="Test 2" />
      <p>
        Let's select the <strong>Channels</strong> perspective. You will see many channels.
        We are going to copy a page from the source (English / US) channel to the target (Dutch /
        Belgium) channel.
        So, please make sure that the target (Dutch / Belgium) channel should have a preview mode configuration.
      </p>
      <p>
        <em>Note: </em>
        if a channel doesn't have a preview mode configuration, it won't be
        available in the dropdown of the <strong>Page Settings</strong> dialog
        as a target channel when copying a page.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen03.png" alt="Test 3" />
      <p>
        Now let's edit the source (English / US) channel.
        And click on the Pages link and create a new page called "test".
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen04.png" alt="Test 4" />
      <p>
        Add three <strong>Simple Content</strong> catalog components in the "test" page.
        And link to each of the documents under the "content" folder and save the page.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen05.png" alt="Test 5" />
      <p>
        Click on the <strong>Page Settings</strong> link and select the target (Dutch / Belgium) channel
        to copy the "test" page.
      </p>
      <p>
        <em>Note: </em>
        if you don't see a target channel in the dropdown, please make sure that the target channel should have
        a preview mode configuration in prior.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen07.png" alt="Test 7" />
      <p>
        Open the target (Dutch / Belgium) channel and select the copied page, "test".
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen08.png" alt="Test 8" />
      <p>
        You will see the copied page, "test", with the copied documents together.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen09.png" alt="Test 9" />
      <p>
        Also browse the content folder of the target (Dutch / Belgium) channel. You will see all the three documents
        copied from the source (English / US) channel.
      </p>
      <img src="images/testscreen10.png" alt="Test 10" />
      <p>
        <em>Note: </em>
        All the linked documents from the copied page are copied together into the target channel content folder.
        However, the copied documents are taken offline after copying.
        Editors are responsible for publishing those copied documents afterward.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
